BO LORA

Senior Design Technologist and web expert

I'm an experienced web professional who has witnessed the evolution of the internet. I'm passionate about engaging in every facet of web development, from strategic planning and design to development. With a deep understanding of both technical and business requirements, I'm adept at addressing the challenges that often impede teams in achieving speed while staying committed to user-centric approaches. I firmly believe that leveraging rich, data-driven HTML prototypes represents the most potent approach for crafting innovative future-state designs for large corporate websites and web-enabled solutions.

Summary of Qualifications

HTML Prototype Engineering
☐ Experienced in the latest HTML/UI frontend technologies
☐ Can set up HTML prototype development environments
☐ Have developed HTML prototype development infrastructure with Angular and React
☐ Can create localized multilingual dynamic prototypes
UI/Web Development
☐ JavaScript: React, jQuery, Angular, Knockout, underscore/lodash, etc.
☐ HTML/CSS: Twitter Bootstrap, Less, SASS
□ Data services: AJAX, AWS API gateway, AWS Lambda
□ Database: SQL(MySQL), NOSQL (MongoDB, DynamoDB)
☐ Development tools: Webpack, Babel, Git, Node.js, NPM, Jira
□ Cloud/Hosting: Rackspace, AWS, HostGator
Information Architecture
☐ Experienced authoring site flow diagrams and wireframes
☐ Have conducted content inventories and taxonomy assessments
User Centered Design (UCD)
☐ Design thinking facilitation
☐ User centered goals through surveys, focus groups and contextual inquiries
 Prototypes from low fidelity to high fidelity using advanced techniques User research activities: heuristic reviews, expert evaluations, usability test planning, & usability tests
Web Strategy
☐ Have conducted numerous competitive analyses
☐ Can identify how websites can align with corporate strategies
☐ Have a clear understanding of how to balance business objectives with technical limitations
☐ Experienced in web project roadmap activities to prioritize web development work
☐ Can implement measures to calculate return on investment (ROI)
☐ Informed about emerging technologies
☐ Solid understanding and active participation in social media and web 2.0

Web Standards and Governance

☐ Have built several design pattern libraries incorporating samples and templates

☐ Can build a process for managing change of design patterns and standards

Process Engineering

	a: a:						
ч.	SixSigr	na aree	en be	It.	tra	ın	inc

- ☐ Experienced in identifying problems through the use of methods such as Ichikawa diagrams, Kano models & process maps.
- ☐ Experienced in identifying and capturing Critical To Quality (CTQ) statements and Voice of Customer (VOC).
- Experienced in clearly identifying customer goals and balancing them with business objectives.

Work Experience

Senior Design Technologist - 5/2022 - present Amazon Web Services (AWS), Austin, TX

Lead a team of design technologists for AWS Industry Products prototyping team. Work to accelerate product design and development for automotive, healthcare and life sciences, media/entertainment/sports, supply chain, fintech, and manufacturing industry segments. Our team's activities cover a full spectrum from business development, ideation, business requirements, design, prototyping, user testing, and front-end development.

Senior Design Technologist - 5/2016 - 5/2022 Amazon Business, Austin, TX

Founding member of the Amazon Business User Experience team. Worked over 4 years in building the Business UI (BUI) design system to enable scalable business experiences for the Business Account experience (BAX) which provides Amazon.com business customers an interface to manage their accounts. As part of a two person team that worked on this unfunded initiative we built a comprehensive design system which provided a comprehensive collection of reusable patterns, React components, responsive layouts, design tokens, and css framework designed to meet the needs of Amazon Business. These efforts lead to the creation of a fully funded program with a team of over 10 people to continue design and development.

Principal Software Development Engineer UXPrototyping/UIFrontEnd - 9/2011 - 5/2016 Dell, Computer, RoundRock, TX

Worked in the Creative Design Experience organization to create the future vision of Dell.com through the use of innovative HTML prototype technologies. Developed UX design infrastructure tools to help web designers and UX architects in the process of UX prototyping. Lead Dell.com's effort in adopting a common UI CSS framework based on Twitter Bootstrap.

Senior User Experience InformationArchitect – Team leader - 6/2009- 9/2011 Travelocity, Inc, Dallas, TX

Team leader for Information Architects and Web Designers in the Travelocity Global Trips team. The team was responsible for the design of a global template system which is used by Travelocity global companies and other travel partners. Provide leadership in specifying new functionality in flight and hotel shopping paths. Facilitate and lead Joint Application Design sessions to provide business partners with ways to brainstorm and vet ideas for innovative solutions. The team delivers prototypes using Axure and provides specifications for all interaction with wireframes, comps and presentations. Manage and interact with offshore design, development and testing resources in an agile development environment.

Senior Business Consultant - 11/2006-04/2009 BearingPoint Inc, SanAntonio, TX (Remote)

Provided businesses the required knowledge to change or create processes for sound user centered web design. Top experience in Agile development methodologies incorporating SixSigma techniques to implement best-in-class quality measures and accountability. Can provide proven wireframe and rapid web prototype techniques that assure the greatest level of communication of requirements from business partners to development partners. Most recently worked with a large client in the telecommunications industry to help build an eCommerce web design team.

Web Producer - 12/2001 7/2006 USAA, San Antonio, TX

Provided specialized leadership, user interaction design expertise and project management skills throughout web application development lifecycle to effectively achieve business stakeholder objectives and target audience expectations. Planned and integrated project user interaction design activities, consistent with project management and business requirements. Helped develop and refine user experience and corporate branding strategies, design requirements and specifications and quality assurance processes while adhering to established standards, guidelines and methodologies. Developed and managed project plans and schedules, budgets, resource allocations, risk mitigation strategies and reporting and tracking activities. Provided ongoing direction and leadership for team members and/or matrixed employees. Responsible for completion of web design project deliverables.

Globalization Business Consultant - 2/2001 7/2001 SDL International LPC, Maidenhead UK, (Central US Region)

Provided sales support as business consultant regarding end-to-end globalization solutions for large scale websites, software and document repositories. This included technical responses to help customers understand the integration issues regarding globalization infrastructure software. Provided technical and business thought leadership for the sales force and industry by publishing white papers and a weekly industry newsletter. Developed and delivered seminars presenting the value proposition of globalization, internationalization development issues, and the principals of multilingual content management systems. Developed consulting engagement offering which included methodology, pre-sales materials and documentation. Developed strategic and technical partnership agreements to form complementing alliances.

Globalization Business Consultant - 9/2000 12/2000

Uniscape, Inc., Sunnyvale, CA (Central US Region)

Provided sales support as business consultant regarding end-to-end globalization solutions for large scale websites, software and document repositories. Provided strategic consulting services to establish globalization business objectives and ROI. Managed system integration and delivery of globalization infrastructure solutions.

Information Architect - 8/1996-8/2000 Motorola, Inc., Austin, TX

Information Architect/Creative Lead for www.digitaldna.com. Interfaced with the creative, content, intelligence and web hosting teams to specify architecture of the site (information and technical) and maintain brand consistency. Managed Ad Agency relationship to assure effective strategies to meet business objectives. Worked on several intranet efforts as well as other external websites. Specified and executed on the re-architecture of information for the Motorola semiconductor site www.motsps.com and developed content management processes and systems for these sites.

VP Internet Marketing - 9/1995 -8/1996 Connect International, Inc., SanAntonio, TX

Part of the founding team for one San Antonio's first Internet service providers. Helped customers market their businesses on the web by developing web marketing plans, web sites and applications.

CreativeDirector - 2/1993 -9/1995 Image Matters, Inc, San Antonio, TX

Led the design and creation of brochures, ads, billboards, advertising specialties, posters, etc. Designed integrated radio and print campaigns. Was responsible for business development activities such as making presentations and responding to RFPs.

Independent Computer Consultant - 10/1992 -2/1993 Self Employed, San Antonio, TX

Taught various computer classes like Microsoft Windows, Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Lotus 123, PageMaker. Designed and installed networked desktops for offices.

Field Engineer - 2/1989 -9/1992

Bolt, Beranek and Newman, Inc. (BBN), Stuttgart, Germany

Evaluated, specified and installed x.25 packet switching nodes and equipment for the ArpaNet, later known as the Defense Data Network, predecessor of the internet. Worked with Cisco routers, T1, fiber optic and other communication devices. Developed an installation reporting application for all field engineers in Europe to use.

Cryptographic Electronic Technician - 5/1983 -1/1989 US Army, Frankfurt, Germany

Work on cryptographic equipment for teletype, radio teletype, FM, and peer to peer computer communications. Possessed a Top Secret clearance and worked classified NATO communication systems.

Education

University of Maryland, Baltimore, Maryland Bachelor's degree work Information Systems Management

Skills

Agile Web Development (HTML Prototyping, Axure, Figma, Certified ScrumMaster), Web Development (ASP, PHP, HTML/XHTML, MVC, Sass, design tokens), JavaScript (ReactJS, web components, jQuery, AngularJS, NodeJS), Project Management (Asana, MS Project, Excel, Version One, Trac, Jira), SixSigma (Green belt training), Business Process Engineering.